Guide to the Human Rights Watch Records: Helsinki Watch,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VIII: New York Office Files, 1975-1996
  - Helsinki Watch
    - Helsinki Watch
      - Press Releases
        - Lithuania--Vilnius--USSR Civilian Rights Violations, 1990 March 27 (Box 33, Folder 57)
        - Lithuania--Vilnius--USSR Occupation, 1990 April 2 (Box 33, Folder 58)
        - Lithuania--USSR Collective Punishment of the Lithuanian People, 1990 April 24 (Box 33, Folder 59)
        - USSR--Orlov, Yuri--Visa Denial, 1990 May 25 (Box 33, Folder 60)
        - Turkey--Prison Visit, 1990 July 5 (Box 33, Folder 61)
        - Romania--Munteanu, Marian (student leader)—detention, 1990 August 2 (Box 33, Folder 62)
        - Greece--Turkish Minority, 1990 September 30 (Box 33, Folder 63)
        - Turkey--Kurd Report, 1990 October 15 (Box 33, Folder 64)
        - USSR--Kazakhstan--Gorbachev Letter, 1990 October 17 (Box 33, Folder 65)
        - Romania, 1990 October 23 (Box 33, Folder 66)
        - Poland, 1990 December 11 (Box 33, Folder 67)
        - Turkey, 1991 January 11 (Box 33, Folder 68)
        - USSR--Azerbaidzhan--State of Emergency, 1991 January 19 (Box 33, Folder 69)
        - Latvia, 1991 January 22 (Box 33, Folder 70)
        - Greece, 1991 January 31 (Box 33, Folder 71)
        - Yugoslavia, 1991 January 31 (Box 34, Folder 1)
        - Yugoslavia, 1991 February 11 (Box 34, Folder 2)
        - Baltics—Gorbachev, 1991 March 11 (Box 34, Folder 3)
        - Yugoslavia, 1991 March 15 (Box 34, Folder 4)
        - United States--Los Angeles—Police, 1991 March 21 (Box 34, Folder 5)
        - USSR, 1991 March 27 (Box 34, Folder 6)
        - Turkey, 1991 April 2 (Box 34, Folder 7)
        - Greece, 1991 April 4 (Box 34, Folder 8)
        - Turkey, 1991 April 4 (Box 34, Folder 9)
        - USSR, 1991 May 10 (Box 34, Folder 10)
        - USSR, 1991 June 10 (Box 34, Folder 11)
        - Albania, 1991 June 17 (Box 34, Folder 12)
        - Yugoslavia--Access Violence, 1991 July 3 (Box 34, Folder 13)
        - USSR, 1991 July 8 (Box 34, Folder 14)
        - Turkey--Human Rights Monitors, 1991 July 9 (Box 34, Folder 15)
        - USSR, 1991 July 29 (Box 34, Folder 16)
        - USSR, 1991 August 6 (Box 34, Folder 17)
        - Turkey, 1991 August 11 (Box 34, Folder 18)
        - USSR, 1991 August 19 (Box 34, Folder 19)
        - USSR, 1991 September 27 (Box 34, Folder 20)
        - Yugoslavia, 1991 December 6 (Box 34, Folder 21)
        - USSR, 1991 December 9 (Box 34, Folder 22)
        - Yugoslavia, 1992 January 23, (2 Folders) (Box 34, Folder 23-24)
        - Turkey, 1992 January 27 (Box 34, Folder 25)
        - Poland, 1992 May 13 (Box 34, Folder 26)
        - South Ossetia--Refugees, 1992 June (Box 34, Folder 27)
        - Turkey--Kurdish Massacre, 1992 June (Box 34, Folder 28)
        - USSR--Armed Conflict, 1992 June (Box 34, Folder 29)
        - Turkey--Journalists--Killed, 1992 June (Box 34, Folder 30)
        - Turkey--Deaths in Detention, 1992 June (Box 34, Folder 31)
        - Romania--Prisons, 1992 June 17 (Box 34, Folder 32)
        - Turkey--Human Rights Activist Murdered, 1992 July (Box 34, Folder 33)
        - Yugoslavia, 1992 July 1 (Box 34, Folder 34)
        - USSR-Russia, 1992 July 9 (Box 34, Folder 35)
        - Turkey--Journalists, 1992 August (Box 34, Folder 36)
        - Bosnia, 1992 August 7 (Box 34, Folder 37)
        - Bosnia-Hercegovina Report, 1992 August 12, (2 Folders) (Box 34, Folder 38-39)
        - Russia--Report: Russian Residence and Travel Restrictions, 1992 August 13 (Box 34, Folder 40)
        - Germany--Romanian Gypsies, 1992 September 24 (Box 34, Folder 41)
        - Turkey, 1992 October 6 (Box 34, Folder 42)
        - Turkmenistan, 1992 November 5 (Box 34, Folder 43)
        - Uzbekistan, 1992 December 10 (Box 34, Folder 44)
        - Bosnia, 1992 December 18 (Box 34, Folder 45)
        - Tajikistan, 1992 December 18 (Box 34, Folder 46)
        - Turkey, 1992 December 29 (Box 34, Folder 47)
        - Tajikistan, 1993 January 21 (Box 34, Folder 48)
        - Turkey--Mumcu, Ugur (newspaper columnist)--Murder, 1993 January 28 (Box 34, Folder 49)
        - Turkey, 1993 February (Box 34, Folder 50)
        - Bosnia-Hercegovina--Peace Negotiations--Vance Letter, 1993 February3 (Box 34, Folder 51)
        - Uzbekistan, 1993 February 10 (Box 34, Folder 52)
        - Turkey, 1993 February 23 (Box 34, Folder 53)
        - Turkey--Detention Deaths, 1993 February (Box 34, Folder 54)
        - Turkey—Killings, 1993 March (Box 34, Folder 55)
        - Russia--Yeltsin--Russian Troop Deployment, 1993 (Box 34, Folder 56)
        - Bosnia--War Crimes, 1993 April 18 (Box 34, Folder 57)
        - Uzbekistan--Political Dismissals, 1993 April, 1993 (Box 34, Folder 58)
        - Bulgaria--Police Violence--Gypsies, 1993 April, 1993 (Box 34, Folder 59)
        - Turkey--Killings, 1993 April (Box 35, Folder 1)
        - Germany--Legislation--Refugees, 1993 May 27 (Box 35, Folder 2)
        - Serbia, 1993 May 28 (Box 35, Folder 3)
        - Northern Ireland, 1993 May (Box 35, Folder 4)
        - Turkey--Detention Deaths, 1993 June (Box 35, Folder 5)
        - Turkey--Sivas Cultural Festival, 1993 July 6 (Box 35, Folder 6)
        - Yugoslavia, 1993 July (Box 35, Folder 7)
        - Turkey, 1993 July 29 (Box 35, Folder 8)
        - Nagorno Karabakh (NKAO), 1993 July (Box 35, Folder 9)
        - Turkey, 1993 August 18 (Box 35, Folder 10)
        - Yugoslavia, 1993 August (Box 35, Folder 11)
        - Poland, 1993 August (Box 35, Folder 12)
        - Russia, 1993 December (Box 35, Folder 13)
        - Kosovo, 1993 (Box 35, Folder 14)
      - Published Articles, 1993 January-May (Box 35, Folder 15)
      - Staff Meetings, 1993-1994, (3 Folders) (Box 35, Folder 16-18)
      - Tax Returns, 1981-1982 (Box 35, Folder 19)
      - Visas and Photographs--Helsinki Watch Personnel, 1993 (Box 35, Folder 20)
      - Abuses--Human Rights--Accountability for, 1989-1993, (2 Folders) (Box 35, Folder 21-22)
      - American Bar Association (ABA), 1986-1987 (Box 35, Folder 23)
      - Amnesty--State Crimes, 1988 (Box 35, Folder 24)
      - Andreescu, Gabriel (member, Group for Social Dialogue)--Internship Application, 1990 July (Box 35, Folder 25)
      - Balkans, 1990 (Box 35, Folder 26)
      - Baltic States--Contacts, 1991-1992 (Box 35, Folder 27)
      - Bard College, 1988-1989 (Box 36, Folder 1)
      - Beyond War, 1989 (Box 36, Folder 2)
      - Brady, Kristin, “Human Rights and 'Free Elections'”, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 3)
      - Burkhalter, Holly, 1983-1985 (Box 36, Folder 4)
      - CFJ Clearinghouse on the Central and East European Press, 1993 (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - The Charta 77 Foundation, 1987-1990, (2 Folders) (Box 36, Folder 6-7)
      - Charter 88, 1989 (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Charter of Paris for a New Europe, 1990-1991, (2 Folders) (Box 36, Folder 9-10)
      - Commonwealth Human Rights Initiative, 1990 (Box 36, Folder 11)
      - Commonwealth of Independent States (CIS)--Past Abuses, 1990-92 (Box 36, Folder 12)
      - CSCE--Helsinki Final Act, 1975 (Box 36, Folder 13)
      - Congressional Friends of Human Rights Monitors--List, 1992-1993 (Box 36, Folder 14)
      - Constitutional Courts--East European, 1992 (Box 36, Folder 15)
      - Helsinki Accords
        - General, 1975 (Box 36, Folder 16)
        - Press Clips, 1982 (Box 36, Folder 17)
        - Helsinki Final Act
          - Status of Signatories, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 18)
          - Summaries, 1975-1977 (Box 36, Folder 19)
        - CSCE
          - Creation, 1976 June 3 (Box 36, Folder 20)
          - General, 1978-1981 (Box 36, Folder 21)
        - United States--Domestic Compliance
          - General, 1979 April (Box 37, Folder 1)
          - Helsinki Watch Subcommittee, 1979 December 10 (Box 37, Folder 2)
          - Helsinki Watch Subcommittee--Reports and Contents, undated. (Box 37, Folder 3)
          - Helsinki Watch Subcommittee--Domestic Compliance Reports--Correspondence, 1980-1982 (Box 37, Folder 4)
        - 10th Anniversary
          - General, 1985 (Box 37, Folder 5)
          - Press Clips, 1985, (2 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 6-7)
        - 15th Anniversary, 1990 July (Box 37, Folder 8)
        - Kampelman, Max, 1980-1987 (Box 37, Folder 9)
        - Madrid Conference, 1980
          - Pre-Conference Plans, 1979-1980 (Box 37, Folder 10)
          - Concluding Document, 1980 (Box 37, Folder 11)
          - Reports, 1979-1981 (Box 37, Folder 12)
        - Madrid Office
          - Correspondence, 1980 November (Box 38, Folder 1)
          - Correspondence--Personnel, 1980 (Box 38, Folder 2)
          - Public Members--Lists, 1980 (Box 38, Folder 3)
          - Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 38, Folder 4)
          - General, 1980-1981 (Box 38, Folder 5)
        - Madrid Conderence
          - Preparations, 1982 (Box 38, Folder 6)
          - Correspondence, 1982-1983, (5 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 7-11)
          - Help and Action--Correspondence, 1980 (Box 38, Folder 12)
          - Expenses, 1980, (2 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 13-14)
          - Follow-up from, 1980 March (Box 39, Folder 1)
          - Follow-up with Kiernan, Bruce Alan (Director, Madrid Office), 1980 (Box 39, Folder 2)
          - Public Members--Lists, 1980 (Box 39, Folder 3)
          - Speeches, 1982-1983, (2 Folders) (Box 39, Folder 4-5)
          - Zurich Meeting, 1980 March 6 (Box 39, Folder 6)
        - Helsinki Commission, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 7)
        - Helsinki Final Act--Implementation, 1985 April-October (Box 39, Folder 8)
        - Ottawa Conference
          - Proposals, undated (Box 39, Folder 9)
          - Correspondence, 1985 May (Box 39, Folder 10)
          - Materials, 1985 May (Box 39, Folder 11)
        - CSCE
          - Hearings, 1985 October 3 (Box 39, Folder 12)
        - Human Contacts Experts Meeting (Bern), 1986, (2 Folders) (Box 40, Folder 1-2)
        - Vienna Conference, 1986
          - General, 1986 (Box 40, Folder 3)
          - Press Clips--Human Rights Violations, 1986 (Box 40, Folder 4)
          - Follow-up Meeting
            - General, 1986-1987 (Box 40, Folder 5)
            - Speeches, 1987 (Box 40, Folder 6)
            - Concluding Document, 1987 (Box 40, Folder 7)
        - Vienna Conference (1988)
          - General (1988), 1987-1988 (Box 41, Folder 1)
          - Zimmermann, Warren, 1988 April 15 (Box 41, Folder 2)
          - Follow-up Meeting, 1989 January (Box 41, Folder 3)
        - Helsinki Final Act--Implementation, 1988-1989 (Box 41, Folder 4)
        - Paris Meeting, 1989 (Box 41, Folder 5)
        - Helsinki Process--Institutionalization, 1989-1991 (Box 41, Folder 6)
        - Copenhagen Meeting, 1990 May-June (Box 41, Folder 7)
        - Geneva Meeting--National Minorities, 1991 (Box 41, Folder 8)
        - Moscow Meeting--Concluding Document, 1991 (Box 41, Folder 9)
        - Helsinki Process Documents, 1991-1993 (Box 41, Folder 10)
        - Speeches, 1992 October (Box 41, Folder 11)
        - Budapest Document, 994 (Box 41, Folder 12)
        - Publications, 1978-1979 (Box 41, Folder 13)
      - Council of Europe
        - General, 1989-1990, 1993-1994, (2 Folders) (Box 42, Folder 1-2)
        - Reports, 1992-1993 (Box 42, Folder 3)
      - Death Penalty, 1987-1988 (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - Democracy Project, 1983 (Box 42, Folder 5)
      - East-West Institute, 1979 (Box 42, Folder 6)
      - Eastern Europe
        - Anti-Semitism, 1991-1992 (Box 42, Folder 7)
        - Decommunization, 1992 (Box 42, Folder 8)
        - Elections (1990), 1990 (Box 42, Folder 9)
        - Free Speech Conference--Proposal, 1991 (Box 42, Folder 10)
        - Press Clips, 1981-1988 (Box 42, Folder 11)
        - Proposal: Expand Helsinki Watch into Eastern Europe, 1990 (Box 42, Folder 12)
        - Research
          - General, 1984-1987, (4 Folders) (Box 43, Folder 1-4)
          - Reports--CSCE, 1987-1991 (Box 43, Folder 5)
          - Reports--CSCE, 1992-1994 (Box 44, Folder 1)
          - General, 1988, (2 Folders) (Box 44, Folder 2-3)
          - General, 1988-1990, 1992, (4 Folders) (Box 45, Folder 1-4)
        - Komisar, Lucy--Notes, 1985 (Box 46, Folder 1)
        - Leadership, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 2)
        - Schwartz, Herman, 1992-1994 (Box 46, Folder 3)
        - Secret Police, 1990-1992 (Box 46, Folder 4)
        - Syllabus: “Human Rights in Eastern Europe”, 1987 (Box 46, Folder 5)
        - Testimonies--House Appropriations Subcommittee on Foreign Operations, 1989 (Box 46, Folder 6)
        - Trip, 1987-1988 (Box 46, Folder 7)
        - United States, 1988 (Box 46, Folder 8)
        - Women, undated (Box 46, Folder 9)
      - Economic and Social Rights, 1988 (Box 46, Folder 10)
      - Ethnic Minorities, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 11)
      - European Commission, 1993-1994 (Box 46, Folder 12)
      - European Community, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 13)
      - European Parliament, 1993-1994 (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Feller, Gordon (journalist), 1993-1994 (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Fanton, Jonathan (President, New School for Social Research), 1992-1994 (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Fitzpatrick, Cathy (Helsinki Watch Researcher), 1986-1987 (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Freedom House, 1977-1985 (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Fundraising--Contributions, 1988 (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - Government Officials, 1991-1993 (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - Gueft, Esther--Central Asia Report, 1991-1993 (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - Gypsies, 1990-1991 (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Harvard Law School--Human Rights Program, 1988 (Box 47, Folder 10)
      - Helsinki Citizens Assembly, 1991 (Box 47, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence--General, 1992 (Box 47, Folder 12)
      - Mailing List (Revisions), 1992 (Box 47, Folder 13)
      - Human Rights Covenants, 1978-1980 (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - International Council of Scientific Unions, undated (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - The International Foundation For the Survival and Development of Humanity, 1988-1989 (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - International Freedom to Publish Committee, 1989 (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - International Law, 1989-1990 (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - Jahangiri-Jeannot, Guissou (researcher), 1989-1994 (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - Journalists
        - General, 1992 (Box 48, Folder 7)
        - International Pen, 1990 (Box 48, Folder 8)
      - Kenney, George D. (U.S. Foreign Service Officer; Yugoslav crisis), 1992 (Box 48, Folder 9)
      - Laber, Jeri
        - A Nation is Dying: Afghanistan Under the Soviets 1979-1987 (1988), 1988 (Box 48, Folder 10)
        - Ideological Exclusion--Poland--Testimony--House Subcommittee on Immigration, Refugees and International Law (June 28, 1984), 1984 (Box 48, Folder 11)
        - Minority Rights--Eastern Europe--Testimony--U.S. Senate Committee on Foreign Relations, 1992 (Box 48, Folder 12)
        - States of Emergency--Speech, 1986 (Box 48, Folder 13)
      - Labor Rights--Burkhalter, Holly--Testimony--House Ways and Means Committee (April 11, 1986), 1986 (Box 48, Folder 14)
      - Lustration, 1992 (Box 48, Folder 15)
      - The Olga Havel Foundation, 1991 (Box 48, Folder 16)
      - Robert Kennedy Memorial Center for Human Rights, 1988 (Box 48, Folder 17)
      - Mechanism--CSCE, 1989 (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Minority Rights Group, 1987, 1989-1990 (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - Monitors, 1992 (Box 49, Folder 3)
      - National Council of Churches, 1979-1982 (Box 49, Folder 4)
      - National Endowment for Democracy
        - General, 1983-1984, 1986-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 49, Folder 5-6)
        - Association of American Publishers--Publishers Dispute, 1984-1985 (Box 49, Folder 7)
      - Neave Trust Research Project on Freedom of Scientists, 1981-1982 (Box 49, Folder 8)
      - Press--Correspondence, 1985 (Box 49, Folder 9)
      - Prison Project
        - General, 1988-1989 (Box 49, Folder 10)
        - Conditions, 1984, 1986, 1988 (Box 49, Folder 11)
        - Prisons
          - Czech, 1988-1990 (Box 49, Folder 12)
          - Polish, 1988-1991 (Box 49, Folder 13)
          - Soviet, 1989-1990 (Box 49, Folder 14)
          - Turkish, 1986-1989 (Box 49, Folder 15)
          - United States, 1988-1993 (Box 49, Folder 16)
      - Professional Organizations and Human Rights--Planning Meeting, 1979 (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, 1993-1994 (Box 50, Folder 2)
      - Refugees
        - General, 1986-1989 (Box 50, Folder 3)
        - Eastern Bloc, 1980-1988 (Box 50, Folder 4)
        - Europe and Former Soviet States, 1996 (Box 50, Folder 5)
        - United States--Detention Centers, 1986 (Box 50, Folder 6)
      - Resistance International, undated (Box 50, Folder 7)
      - The Salzburg Conference: “Justice in Times of Transition”, 1992 (Box 50, Folder 8)
      - Schachter, Oscar, Responses to Questions of Senator Javits Relating to the Self-Executing Nature of the Four Treaties on Human Rights, undated (Box 50, Folder 9)
      - Schell, Orville, 1980-1983 (Box 50, Folder 10)
      - Scholastic, Inc., 1994 (Box 50, Folder 11)
      - Siracusa Principles--Derogation--International Commission on Jurists, 1987 (Box 50, Folder 12)
      - Socialist International, 1980 (Box 50, Folder 13)
      - Soros, George, 1993-1994 (Box 50, Folder 14)
      - Soviet Specialist--Resumes, 1991 (Box 50, Folder 15)
      - START Treaty--Congressional Seminar Series, 1990 (Box 50, Folder 16)
      - Transnational Perspectives (magazine), 1982-1985 (Box 50, Folder 17)
      - Trips, 1982-1984, (2 Folders) (Box 51, Folder 1-2)
      - United Nations
        - General, 1992 (Box 51, Folder 3)
        - Human Rights Commission, 1981-1994 (Box 51, Folder 4)
      - United States
        - Bush Report on Eastern Europe, 1990 (Box 51, Folder 5)
        - Abrams, Elliott, 1982-1985 (Box 51, Folder 6)
        - Schifter, Richard, 1988 (Box 51, Folder 7)
        - Schultz, George P.--Meeting with Jeri Laber, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 8)
        - World Report, 1991-1992 (Box 51, Folder 9)
      - US Information Agency, 1984-1987 (Box 51, Folder 10)
      - Voinovich, Vladimir--Reception, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 11)
      - Washington Helsinki Watch Committee for the United States, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 12)
      - Western Europe, 1989-1990, 1993 (Box 51, Folder 13)
      - Western European Groups, 1978-1982 (Box 51, Folder 14)
      - Women’s Rights, 1989 (Box 51, Folder 15)
      - Wye Retreat, 1988 (Box 51, Folder 16)
- Series IX: Washington D.C. Office Files, 1978-1998
  The files consist of correspondence, manuscripts, memorandums, newspaper clippings, photographs and research materials utilized in the development of reports. The files are arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Abkhazia--Press Clips, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Afghanistan
    - Afghan Conflict, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - General, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Press Clips, 1988 January-December, (10 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 4-15)
  - Albania--Women’s Issues, 1992-1996 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Armenia
    - Foreign Policy--United States, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Karabagh Conflict, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Military, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Australia
    - General, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Press Clips, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Austria--Women’s Issues, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Azerbaijan
    - Foreign Policy
      - Turkey, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - United States, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Karabagh Conflict--Air Attacks, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Military, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Nakhichevan, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Baltic States--Human Rights Watch--Missions, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Belgium--Women’s Issues, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Bosnia
    - General, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - General, 1996, 1998, (3 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
    - Hearing: “Sanjak Hearing” (Congressional Human Rights Caucus, (1996 September 12), 1990-1996 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Press Clips, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Report: Update: Non-Compliance with the Dayton Accords, 1996 August (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - War Crimes
      - Correspondence, 1992-1996 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - G-7 Outreach Response, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Tribunal
        - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 9)
        - Indictment, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Bulgaria--General, 1992-1998 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Canada
    - Contacts and Organizations, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - General, 1987-1995 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Passion Killings
      - General, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Case Work, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Press Clips, 1991-1994 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Women
      - Refugees--Asylum Seekers--Cases, 1990-1995 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Status, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Croatia
    - Contacts, 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1994-1998 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Cyprus
    - General, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Women and Labor, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Czechoslovakia
    - General, 1991-1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Press Clips, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Reproductive Rights, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Czech Republic--Contacts, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Denmark
    - Women’s Issues, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Eastern Europe
    - Press Clips, 1990-1993 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Women’s Issues, 1990-1994 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - England
    - Press Clips, 1990-1995 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Reproductive Rights, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - UK--Northern Ireland--Women’s Issues, 1990-1993 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Europe
    - General, 1983-1994, (2 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 16-17)
    - European Community, 1992-1997 (Box 4, Folder 18)
      [restricted until 2073]
  - Former Yugoslavia
    - Bosnia
      - General, 1992-1996 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Congressional Letters, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Rape, 1992-1995 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Croatia, 1992-1996 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Dayton Accord, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Press Clips, 1992 September-1993 January, (5 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 5-9)
    - Press Clips, 1993 February-May 1-15, (5 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 1-5)
    - Press Clips, 1993 May 16-31-September, (6 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 1-6)
    - Report: Bringing the Perpetrators of Rape in the Balkans to Justice, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Serbia, 1993-1995 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Slovenia, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Women’s Issues, 1992-1996, (2 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 4-5)
  - France--Women’s Issues, 1989-1996 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Georgia--Human Rights Watch--Mission (1993), 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Germany
    - General, 1990-1995 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Reproductive Rights, 1990-1995 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Greece
    - General, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Reproductive Rights, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Hungary
    - Press Clips, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Reproductive Rights, 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Women’s Issues, 1990-1992 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Ireland
    - Reproductive Rights, 1990-1993 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Reproductive Rights, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Women’s Issues, 1988-1995 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Italy
    - Reproductive Rights, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Women’s Issues, 1993-1996 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Nagorno-Karabagh
    - CSCE/International Bodies, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Foreign Mercenaries, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Press Clips--General, 1992-1994 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Prisoners, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Netherlands--Women’s Issues, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Norway--Women’s Issues, 1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Poland
    - Conference on Security and Cooperation in Europe (CSCE), 1983 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Contacts and Organizations, 1992-1994 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Press Clips, 1988 January-June, (6 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 14-19)
    - Press Clips, 1988 July-December, (6 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 1-6)